# Tahir Özdemir

E-mail: me [AT] tahirozdemir [DOT] com

Online Resume: cv.tahirozdemir.com

Web: me.tahirozdemir.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I have experience in C-family languages and Python. Furthermore, I used them for robotic programming with ROS. Also, I developed some little software with Java and Javascript (Node JS). I used MsSQL and MongoDB for database parts of my projects.

I have worked with people who were in different time-zones with a home-office system for one of my previous projects. Thus, I can say that I am suitable for both classic and home-office working style. I am currently improving myself to be better in robotics and AI. I am also interested in CUDA programming. I always have enthusiasm for new technologies. Besides all of these I am blogging on both Medium and my domain.

#### **EDUCATION**

- 2019 - Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Computer Engineering, GPA: 3,70

#### **SKILLS**

# - Programming

O I have developed projects with various programming languages such as C, C++, C# and Python. I have used my programming skills for the applications of following courses: Artificial Intelligence, Recommender Systems, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming (C#), Computer Architecture, Data Security, System Programming (Raspberry Pi).

#### - Database Development/Management

 I have used MsSQL and MongoDB for database parts of my projects. Thus, I can say that I have basic understand for both of SQL and NoSQL database types.

#### - Game Development

o I have made games for both Android and Windows platforms with Unity. Furthermore, I was a member of a game development team, whose members were all around the world, as a C# programmer.

#### - Language

Turkish: Native

o English: Intermediate

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# - OTEK A.Ş., Developer/Researcher, 2019-Still

I have started to work here after my internship. So,

- o I am actively contributing a TUBITAK project which is titled as 'Development of Autonomous Transport Vehicles and Human-Machine / Machine-Machine Interfaces for Smart Factories'. (Contact No: 116E731)
- o I am responsible for various parts of project such as solving task scheduling problem, database development, simulation etc.

#### - Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Developer/Researcher Intern, 2017-2019

- o I contributed a TUBITAK project which is titled as 'Development of Autonomous Transport Vehicles and Human-Machine / Machine-Machine Interfaces for Smart Factories'. (Contact No: 116E731)
- o I was responsible for various parts of project such as solving task scheduling problem, database development, simulation etc.

#### - Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Student Assistant, 2017-2018

 I have taken part as an assistant in the Introduction to Programming and Digital Systems classes. This experience gave me the ability of understanding different views on subjects.

#### **PROJECTS**

# - 'Performing Simulated Annealing Algorithm on GPU and CPU-GPU Performance Evaluation', TÜBİTAK 2209-B, 2018-2019

- This was my final project for my bachelor's degree. The aim was solving a
  task scheduling problem with an improved version of Simulated Annealing
  Algorithm. The algorithm was developed with CUDA library and problem
  solved by GPUs.
- Project is approved by TUBITAK and we got financial support. (Contact No: 1139B411801155)

#### SIDE/SCHOOL PROJECTS

# - GitHub Markdown Editor, Go Project, 2019

 It allows users to perform CRUD operation on markdown files in their GitHub repositories. Detailed information can be reached at <u>GitHub page</u> of the project.

#### - Autonomous Robot Simulation, ROS & Gazebo Project, 2017

 This project is for Formal Languages and Automata class. It represents a simple state machine. Robotnic AGVS and Neuronics Katana Arm were used for simulation. Detailed information can be reached at <u>GitHub page</u> of the project.

#### - Turret Defence, Android Game (Unity), 2016

It is a simple tower defence game that players aim the best time. Except the
music, all parts of it were developed by me in a week. It can be found at
<u>SlimeMe Market</u>.

# **CONFERENCE PAPERS**

- T. Ozdemir, A. Cibi, A. Yazici, Solution of Task Scheduling Problem for Autonomous Transfer Vehicles on GPU-CPU and Performance Evaluation [abstract], In: 3rd International Conference on Engineering And Innovation; 2019 April 17-21; Belgrade, Serbia
- A. Cibi, T. Ozdemir, I. Saricicek, A. Yazici, Scheduling of pick-up or delivery tasks for autonomous robots via dispatching rules [abstract], In: 29th European Conference On Operational Research; 2018 July 8-11; Valencia, Spain